- Hey.
- Oh, hey.
점심 시간에 일했어?
You work the lunch shift?
응, 곧 상할 것 같은
연어 4kg 챙겨 왔어
Yeah. I've got eight pounds of
salmon that's about to go bad.
요리할 줄 알아?
Do you know
how to cook it?
- 잘 모르는데
- 젠장
- Not really.
- Damn it.
차라리 치킨을 해방시킬 걸
Should have liberated
the iffy chicken.
오늘은 신경질적 교수님이랑
무슨 계획 있어?
What are you and Professor
Fussyface up to tonight?
블루레이로 스타워즈 보려고
Star Wars on Blu-ray.
천 번 넘게 보지 않았어?
Haven't you seen that movie,
like, a thousand times?
블루레이는 달라
Not on Blu-ray.
블루레이로 겨우 두 번 봤어
Only twice on Blu-ray.
Oh, Leonard.
나도 알아,
고해상도의 찌질함이지
I know, it's
high-resolution sadness.
오늘 영화보려고 했는데
Well, I'm going to take myself
out to a movie tonight.
같이 갈래?
You want to go?
그래도 돼?
Really? Do we do that?
무슨 소리야?
What do you mean?
헤어진 이후로 그런 적 없잖아
You know, we haven't spent
time alone together
since we broke up.
데이트 아냐, 레너드
Oh, it's not a date, Leonard.
남자랑 여자가
같이 시간을 보내고
It's just a man and a woman
hanging out, not having sex
섹스로 끝나지 않을 거야
at the end of the night.
내가 나간 데이트는 다 그랬어
Sounds like
most of my dates.
저리 가, 이 괴물아!
SHELDON: Oh, dear Lord, get away
from me, you monster!
무슨 일이지?
What is that about?
충분히 똑똑하고 창의적이니
Well, he's smart
and crazy enough,
실제로 괴물을 만들었을 수도
he may have actually
created a monster.
휘휘, 저리 가!
Shoo, shoo!
Be gone!
대체 무슨 일이야?
What the hell is going on?
창밖에 새가 안 날아가고 있어
There's a bird outside the
window, and he won't go away.
지옥 같은 상황이지
That is the hell
that is going on.
여기엔 벌레나 씨앗 따위 없어
We have no worms or seeds here.
Shoo, shoo.
이젠 새도 무서워하는 거야?
Really? On top of everything
else, you're afraid of birds?
조류공포증이란 거야
It's called ornithophobia.
언젠가는 장애로
인정 받아서
And someday it will
be recognized
법적으로 아파트에
그물을 씌워야 할 거야
as a true disability, and the
landlord will be required by law
to put a giant net
over the building.
그물도 무서워하는 내게는
안타까운 해결책이지만
Which is unfortunate, because
I have a fear of nets.
영화 볼래 말래?
So movies, yes or no?
보자
Movies, yes.
그래, 이따 봐
Great. I'll see you later.
네가 무서워하는 것 보다
쟤가 널 더 무서워할 거야
And remember, he's more afraid
of you than you are of him.
도움이 되지 않아
That doesn't help.
새한테 한 말이야
No, I was talking
to the bird.
저리 가, 새야
Go away, bird. Go away, bird.
Go away, bird.
쉘든, 그냥 무시해
Sheldon, just ignore him.
좋은 생각이야
새들은 주목받는 걸 즐기지
Good idea.
Attention is what birds want.
훨씬 낫군
Oh, much better. All right.
이제 하던 일 마저 해야지
Now I'll just get along
with my life.
(bird squawks)
차 좀 끓여놔, 레너드,
긴 밤이 될 거 같다
Make a pot of tea, Leonard.
It's going to be a long night.
♪ Our whole universe
was in a hot, dense state ♪
♪ Then nearly 14 billion years
ago expansion started... Wait! ♪
♪ The Earth began to cool ♪
♪ The autotrophs began to drool,
Neanderthals developed tools ♪
♪ We built the Wall ♪
♪ We built the pyramids ♪
♪ Math, Science, History,
unraveling the mystery ♪
♪ That all started
with a big bang ♪
♪ Bang! ♪
DC 기타 미국드라마 갤러리
The Big Bang Theory 5x09
The Ornithophobia Diffusion
Original Air Date on November 10, 2011
자막 공대언니
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
(imitates cat meowing)
(meowing louder)
(imitates cat meowing
and hissing)
새 아직도 있어?
The bird's still there?
매는 어떻게 울더라?
Quick, what does
a hawk sound like?
몰라
I don't know--
scree-scree.
야, 그건 갈매기잖아
Please, that's a seagull.
도움이 안 될 거면
가만히 있어
If you're not going
to help, don't help.
좀 봐줘,
너무 차려입었나?
Sorry. Do you think
I'm overdressed?
뭘 하는지에 따라 다르지 뭐
It depends on the activity.
직장검사에는 좀 과하다
For a prostate exam, yes.
베가스에 가는 거면
스팽글 좀 달아
If you're playing Vegas,
I'd add sequins.
페니랑 영화보러 가는 거야
I'm going to the movies
with Penny.
내가 데이트라 생각한다고
오해받고 싶지 않아
I don't want her to think
that I think it's a date.
데이트라고 생각해?
Do you think it's a date?
페니는 내가 그렇게 생각한다고
잘못 생각할 수 있잖아
No, but she might think I think
it's a date even though I don't.
아니면 페니가 그렇게 믿는다고
네가 잘못 생각할 수 있지
Or you might think she thinks you think
it's a date even though she doesn't.
- 생각을 너무 많이 하는 건가?
- 전혀
- Are we overthinking this?
- Not at all.
그래, 그냥 이렇게 입을래
You're right. I'm fine.
I'm wearing this.
블레이저를 입는다고?
그러던가
Really? A blazer?
All right.
여보세요
Yes, hello.
쉘든 쿠퍼 박사입니다
This is Dr. Sheldon Cooper.
2311 노스 로블레스
에버뉴인데요
I'm at 2311 North Robles Avenue.
위험한 야생동물을 목격했어요
I'd like to report
a dangerous wild animal.
큰어치요
A blue jay.
동물관리국 아닌가요?
I'm sorry, this is
Animal Control.
왜 웃는 거죠?
I don't understand the laughter.
아뇨,
집안에 있지는 않아요
No, the bird is not in my home.
집안에 있다면
911에 신고했겠죠
If he was in my home, I
obviously would have called 911.
그쪽도 두려워하는 게
있을거 아닙니까
Sir, I have no doubt that
there are things
that you're frightened of.
아무런 미래가 없는
공무원 자리에 머문다던가
Being stuck in a dead-end
public service job.
아내가 떠날까봐
무서울 수도 있겠죠
Or your wife stepping out on you
미래가 없는
공무원 남편이니까요
because you're stuck in
a dead-end public service job.
아니면 거미도 있고요
Or spiders.
고양이 소리는 이미
냈을 거란 생각이 안 드나요?
Don't you think I tried
making cat noises?
너무 캐주얼한가?
Too casual?
여왕님을 만나기에는
너무 간편하고
For an audience
with the queen, yes.
쓰레기통에 불을 지피고
For an evening of passing
a bottle of fortified wine
패거리랑 와인을 나눠 마실
계획이라면 딱 어울려
around a flaming trash can,
you look great.
(imitates cat snarling
and hissing)
내 정신 좀 봐,
수염이 없네
What am I thinking?
Whiskers.
조금 서두르면
Oh, hey, if we hurry,
제니퍼 애니스톤
신작을 볼 수 있겠다
we can make the new
Jennifer Aniston movie.
Oh, yeah, sure.
멋진 다큐도 있어
There's also
an amazing documentary
남아메리카 강에
댐을 짓는 내용이야
about building a dam
on a river in South America.
제니퍼 애니스톤 영화에는
제니퍼 애니스톤이 있잖아
Okay, but the Jennifer Aniston
movie has Jennifer Aniston,
댐 같은 건 안 나와
and she's not
building a dam.
반박할 수 없네
Can't argue with that.
- 내가 표 살게
- 그래
- I'll get the tickets.
- Okay.
있잖아
Actually, you know what?
영화는 내가
고를 차례인 것 같아
I think it's about time
I picked a movie we see.
고른 적 많잖아
You pick plenty of movies.
아냐, 항상 네가 골랐지
No. You always picked,
매번 똑같았어
and it was always the same.
해변의 별장이
한 시간 반 동안 나오고
An hour and a half of
beach houses in the rain
그러다 여자는 사랑이
바로 옆에 있다는 걸 깨닫지
until the woman turns
around and realizes love
was here all along.
난 재밌던데,
10분 후에 시작이야
Come on, that is a great movie,
and it starts in ten minutes.
난 그런 영화 싫어해
I hate those movies.
- 그렇지 않아
- 맞거든
- No, you don't.
- Yes, I do.
네가 보자고 해서
간 것 뿐이야
The only reason I went is
because you wanted to see them,
섹스도 하고 싶었고
and I wanted to have sex.
매번 산드라 블록
포스터를 보면
To this day, I can't see
a Sandra Bullock movie poster
지루함과 동시에
흥분이 돼
without getting both
bored and aroused.
우리가 사귈 때
Okay, so while we
were going out,
섹스 때문에 뭔가를
좋아하는 척 했다고?
how often would you pretend to like
things just to have sex with me?
항상 그랬어
All the time.
설마
You're kidding.
다시 해볼까?
Does this sound familiar?
신발 쇼핑은
당연히 같이 가고 싶지
I'd love to go
shoe shopping with you.
하이킹?
좋지
Hiking? It's great.
새벽 2시지만
코리아타운은 가고 싶어
It's 2:00 a.m., of course I want
to go to Korea Town and sing
네 친구들이랑
노래방에서 놀자
karaoke with your friends.
누구나 다 좋아할 걸
Who wouldn't?
우린 사귀고 있었잖아
Okay, we were going out.
섹스는 어차피
일어났을 거야
You were going
to get sex anyway.
댐에 관한
3시간 짜리 다큐 후에도?
Really? You would have slept
with me after a three-hour
documentary on dams?
그럴 여자는 없지
No. No woman would.
그래, 이젠 잘 됐잖아
See? Now, that's
the great thing.
우리는 친구 사이고
이건 데이트가 아냐
We're out as friends.
This is not a date.
섹스는 얘기할 것도 없지
Sex is off the table.
수력발전이 일으키는
환경문제에 대해 배우러 가자
So, let's go learn how
hydroelectric power
might not be the environmental
bargain you think it is.
미안, 스포일러였어
Sorry. Spoiler alert.
그래, 알았어
All right, fine.
고마워
Thanks.
표는 11불이야
Tickets are 11 bucks.
데이트 아니잖아
Not a date.
스타워즈 볼 시간이야
Come on, Sheldon,
Star Wars.
재생 시작한다
I'm pushing play.
I mean it.
지금 시작 안 하면
If we don't start soon,
조지 루카스가
또 바꿀 거야
George Lucas is going
to change it again.
직업학교 출신이
도와주면 훨씬 빠를 걸
This would go a lot faster
if you put your trade school
diploma to work
고주파음 발생기를
설정하고 있어
and helped me set up this
high-frequency tone generator.
난 MIT에서 석사 학위를 받았어
I have a Masters degree
from M.I.T.
넌 뭐든 할 수 있다는
자세를 갖고 있어
Yeah, but you've got
a can-do attitude
그게 중요하지
and that's what's important.
왜 그렇게
새를 싫어하는 건데
I really don't get
your problem with birds.
질문은 이렇게 해야지
The question you
should be asking
왜 새들이 나를 싫어하는가
is what is their problem
with me?
내 첫 기억에는 벌새가
유모차를 갑자기 공격했어
My first memory: A hummingbird
dive-bombing my stroller
내 빨대컵에 있던
사과 주스를 노렸던 거지
to get at the apple juice
in my sippy cup.
벌새는 예쁘게 생겼어
Hummingbirds are pretty.
꽃세계에서 벌새는
흡혈귀라 부르지
Hummingbirds are the vampires
of the flower world.
발목 문신을 한다면
벌새가 1순위야
Still my first choice
for an ankle tattoo.
돌고래도 괜찮고,
아직 못 정했어
Or a dolphin--
I go back and forth.
7살 때는 피에 굶주린
닭에 쫓겨 나무에 숨었어
Age seven, a blood-thirsty
chicken chases me up a tree.
12살 때는 까치가
입 안의 보정기를 훔치려 했어
Age 12, a magpie tries to steal
the retainer out of my mouth.
16살 때는 앵무새가
뚱뚱하다고 놀렸어
Age 16, a parrot in a
pet store calls me fat ass.
더 말할 필요도 없지?
Need I go on?
계속해,
영화보다 낫다
Yes, please. This is way better
than the movie.
자, 쉘든
(laughing)
All right, Sheldon,
살인광선이 준비됐어
your bird death ray is ready.
살인광선까지는 아니고
It's not a death ray.
조금 놀라게 만들 초음파야
It's just a little ultrasonic
blast to scare him off.
내게 살인광선이 있었다면
Trust me, if I had a death ray,
여기에 살고 있지 않겠지
I wouldn't be living here.
부귀영화를 누리고 있겠지
I'd be in my lair
enjoying the money
살인광선을 사용하지 않는 대신
인간한테 돈을 받았을 거야
the people of Earth gave me
for not using my death ray.
3, 2, 1
All right, and in three,
two, one.
(pushes button)
강적이네
That is one
tough birdie.
너도 재밌게 봤잖아
Come on, you enjoyed
the movie.
마을에 홍수가 나서
I saw you tearing up
when the village got flooded,
주민들이 이사할 때
눈물도 글썽이던데
and everyone
had to relocate.
아니, 모두 떠나는데
나만 계속 있어야 해서 그랬어
No, I was thinking how come
they get to leave and I can't.
감자튀김 주문할게
I'm going to get some fries.
뭐 먹을래?
You want anything?
- 난 괜찮아
- 정말?
- Uh, no, thanks.
- Are you sure?
괜찮다고 한 다음에
내 것을 반이나 먹잖아
You always say no, and then
you eat half my fries.
네가 싫어하는
바삭한 거로 골라 먹잖아
I just eat the little crispy
ones you don't like.
아니, 아껴두는 거야
No, I love them.
I save them for the end,
네가 다 먹어서
못 먹는 거고
but they're gone
because you ate them.
왜 양보했냐고?
And why did
I let you eat them?
- 섹스 하려고
- 바로 그거야
- To get sex.
- Exactly.
하지만 이건 데이트가 아냐
But this is
not a date.
다시 물어볼게,
뭐 먹을래?
So I ask again,
would you like anything?
그럼 나도 감자튀김
All right, I'd like
an order of fries.
좋아, 5불 내놔
Great. That'll be five dollars.
최고의 시간이야
I am having the best time.
같이 나가자 해서 고마워
I'm so glad you suggested
we do this.
미안해요
Oh, sorry.
괜찮아요
No problem.
뭐 하고 있어요?
What you writing there?
대본이에요
A screenplay.
섹스를 하는 중인
어떤 남자가
Its about a guy whose
roommate is having sex
룸메이트한테 바에 가서
대본 작업이나 하라는 내용이요
and tells him to go to a bar
and work on his screenplay.
'알렉스가 매독에 걸렸으면 좋겠다'
"I Hope Alex Gets Crabs:
The Movie."
아직은 가제에요
- It's a working title.
- Oh. (chuckles)
- 전 케빈이라고 해요
- 페니입니다
- I'm Kevin.
- Oh. Penny.
만나서 반가워요
Nice to meet you.
그럼 즐거운 데이트 하세요
I'll let you get
back to your date.
아뇨, 데이트 아니에요
Oh, no, no.
This isn't a date, no.
맞지?
Right?
맞아
Uh... right.
혹시 작품 중에
제가 아는 게 있을까요?
So have you written anything
I might have seen?
리뷰 사이트 '옐프'에
시간을 많이 보내시나요?
That depends. How much time
do you spend on Yelp?
(light sabers crackling on TV)
(bird squawks outside)
(bird squawking)
이건 말도 안돼
This is ridiculous.
난 텍사스 출신의 성인이야
I'm a grown man from Texas.
백조나 거위처럼
무서운 새가 아냐
This isn't a terrifying bird
like a swan or a goose.
(bird squawking)
그냥 큰어치일 뿐이지
It's just a blue jay.
좀 크긴하네
That's a pretty big blue jay.
하나
One...
둘
two...
셋
three.
Go! Shoo!
Am-scray, ird-bay!
집에 새가 들어왔다
(gasps)
Bird in the apartment!
안돼!
No!
정말 훌륭한 다큐에요
So it is an amazing
documentary.
전기 때문에 댐이 필요하고
They need the electricity from
the dam, but at the same time,
환경도 보호하고 싶어하죠
they want to preserve
the environment.
이럴 수가
You're kidding me.
잠깐 얘기 좀 할까?
Uh, can I see you
for a sec over here?
물론이지
Oh, yeah. Sure.
Just one sec?
No problem.
왜 그래?
What's up?
네가 무슨 생각하는지 알겠어
I know what you're doing.
- 그게 뭔데?
- 일부러 그러고 있잖아
- What am I doing?
- You're going out of your way
데이트가 아니라 해서
저 남자랑 떠드는 거
to talk to that guy because
I said we weren't on a date.
아냐, 잘생겨서 말 걸었어
No, I'm talking to him
because he's cute.
야, 그 정도는 아니잖아
Come on, he's not that cute.
맞거든
Yes, he is.
찌질한 티셔츠에
힙스터 안경까지
With his dorky T-shirt
and his little hipster glasses.
그건 내 패션이잖아
I wear dorky T-shirts
and glasses.
하지만 큰 키에
광대뼈도 두드러진 얼굴이면
Yes, but when you're tall
and have great cheekbones,
같은 옷이 달라 보이지
you're doing it ironically.
그럼 나도 여자들한테 말 걸까?
If that's so, what if I
start talking to a girl?
그럼
You should!
나 진짜 할 거야
I'm serious.
I'll do it.
그래,
저기 여자들 있네
Good! Go! There are some
girls right over there.
뭘 기다려?
What are you waiting for?
모여 있잖아,
무서워
They're in a group.
I'm scared.
쉘든, 우리한테
뭘 기대하는 거야?
Sheldon, what do you
expect us to do?
너네 생물학자잖아
You're biologists.
생물학은 생물을
연구하는 학문이야
Biology is the study
of living things.
저기 생물이 있잖아,
얼른 시작해
That's a living thing;
get cracking.
난 미생물 전공이고
I specialize in microorganisms,
에이미는 뇌를 연구해
and Amy studies brains.
우리 둘 다 새 쫓기를
부전공으로 한 적도 없어
Yeah, neither of us
minored in bird-shooing.
Oh, come now.
학부 수업에
야생동물을 다뤘을 거 아냐
Your undergraduate work
must have included
a varmints and critters class.
들어와,
해치지 않을 거야
Come back in, Sheldon,
he's not going to hurt you.
순해 보여
He looks friendly.
누군가의 애완동물일 수 있어
I think he might
be someone's pet.
베르나데트,
영웅이 될 필요 없어
No, Bernadette, don't be a hero!
너무 귀엽다
Oh, he's a sweetie.
그래, 귀엽네
Yes. It's very sweet.
이제 천천히 움직여
Now, slowly and carefully,
변기에 넣고 물을 내려
flush him down the toilet.
쉘든, 포비아를 극복하려면
Sheldon, the only way
to get past this fear
친해져야 해
is to interact with it.
우체부 아저씨랑 한 것처럼
Just like you did
with the mailman.
매년 새로 인한 사망이
몇 십 건이나 발생해
Every year tens of people around
the world are killed by birds.
난 또 하나의
통계 수치가 되기 싫어
I'm not going to be
another statistic.
얼마나 순한지 봐봐,
와서 인사해
Look how sweet he is.
Come over and say hi.
어서 와
Come on.
할 수 있어
You can do it.
무서워하지 마
Don't be scared.
Come on.
어리광은 그만 부리고
쓰다듬기나 해
Oh, just pet the bird,
you big baby!
(gasps)
해냈다!
I did it!
정말 만졌어
I actually did it.
이제 변기통에 넣어
Okay, now flush him.
레너드, 취미가 뭔가요?
So, Leonard,
what do you do for fun?
음, 그러니까
I'm... let's see.
하이킹
Hiking.
코리아타운
노래방 가기
Karaoke in Koreatown.
그리고 제니퍼 애니스톤
영화를 즐겨봐요
Any Jennifer Aniston movie.
딴짓해서 미안
Hey. Sorry I ditched you.
괜찮아, 계속 딴짓해
- No, it's fine. You can ditch away.
- Oh, no, no.
같이 시간 보내기로 했잖아
We said we were going to
hang out, let's hang out.
괜찮아,
케빈한테 돌아가
It's cool.
Go back to Kevin.
가봐야 한다고 해서
Oh, he had to leave.
흥미롭군
Interesting.
케빈이 없으니까
나랑 놀려고 하는 거네
So now that he's gone,
you want to hang out with me.
이 분이 페니였군요
- This must be Penny.
- Yep.
무슨 말인지 알겠어요
I totally get it.
네? 무슨 말씀인지?
Huh? I'm sorry, get what?
신경 쓰지 마,
저기 남자들 있네
Don't worry about it. You know,
there's some guys over there.
가서 말 걸어
You should go talk to them.
아니, 무슨 말 했는지
알고 싶어
No, no. I want to
know what you told her.
그건 나랑...
That's kind of
between me and...
- 로라
- Laura.
알겠어
Oh. Okay, I see.
얘기 나누는 동안
이건 들었나요?
So while he was telling
you things, did he mention
스타트렉 유니폼이
두 개나 있다고요
he owns, not one,
but two Star Trek uniforms?
- 정말요?
- 네, 입기도 하죠
- Really?
- Yeah. Wears them.
할로윈에만
그러는게 아니에요
Not just for Halloween.
친구야
Hey, pal.
내가 케빈한테
이런 짓은 안 했잖아
You didn't see me telling
Kevin that you thought
넌 냉전이 겨울에만
일어나는 줄 알았다고
cold wars were only
fought in winter.
그럼 나도 보답할게,
이 분께는 비밀로 하지
Okay. Then I'll return the
favor, and I won't tell...
- 로라
- Laura.
- ...Laura
네가 가진 성인물의
반 이상이 애니메이션이란 걸
that half the dirty movies
you own are animated.
케빈한테 배우 활동
얘기를 할 때
When you were telling Kevin
about your acting career,
치즈케익 팩토리라는
삼류 영화에서
did you mention your
long-running role as "Waitress"
'웨이트리스' 역을
장기간 맡고 있다고 말했냐?
in a local production of
The Cheesecake Factory?
네 행운의
천식 호흡기는 어떻고?
Did you tell her about
your lucky asthma inhaler?
'Asthma' 철자는 알아?
Oh, yeah? Spell "asthma."
A-s...
집에 갈래
Take me home.
난 아직 더 있고 싶어
Maybe I'm not done
hanging out with...
그래, 돌아가자
You're right,
it's getting late.
놀랍군
It's remarkable.
공포에 질렸던 시간
All that time spent in fear.
왜 그랬었지?
And for what?
아름다운 동물이야
He's magnificent.
(gasps)
이런
Oh, dear.
깜빡하고 음료를
내오지 않았네
I just realized I haven't
offered you a beverage.
할머니랑 앵무새
생각 난다
Oh, it's just like my grandma
with her parrot.
리모콘 때문에
미쳐버렸을 때와도 비슷해
And after she lost her marbles
with her remote control.
책상 위에 내 폰이 있는데
My phone's on the desk
over there.
사진 좀 부탁할게
Take a picture of us together.
컵, 마우스 패드, 달력 등에
쓸 수 있게 잘 찍어줘
Make it good enough
to go on a mug,
a mouse pad, and a calendar.
네가 비둘기였다면
러비더비라고 부를 텐데
If you were a dove,
I'd call you Lovey-Dovey.
무슨 소리를 하는 거지
Oh. Who am I kidding?
굳이 그런 규칙을
따를 필요는 없지
This isn't a moment for strict
adherence to the literal.
넌 사랑스러우니까,
우리 러비더비야
You're just my little
Lovey-Dovey, aren't you?
뼈가 비어 있어야
사랑받을 수 있는 건가
Guess you gotta
have hollow bones
to get some sugar around here.
누가 키우던 새 같아
I still think he looks
like someone's pet.
포스터를 붙여 놓으면 어떨까
Maybe we should put up posters.
그래, 사진도 넣자
Yes. It should have
a big picture of him,
"잘 키울게요"라는
문구도 추가하고
and the words, "Is this
your bird? Not anymore."
정말 재밌을 거야
We're going to have
so much fun together.
내 적에게
메시지 전달을 하고
You can carry messages
to all my enemies.
다리에 실을 묶어
연처럼 날릴 수도 있어
I can tie a string to your leg
and fly you like a kite.
키울 생각이면
새장 빌려줄게
If you're keeping him,
I've got a cage you can borrow.
실험용 원숭이 중 하나가
바나나 껍질을 밟고
One of the test monkeys
slipped on a banana peel
목이 부러졌어
and broke his neck.
비극적이면서 웃겼지
It was both tragic
and hysterical.
무슨 소리야
Nonsense.
러비더비는 새장에 두지 않아
No. Lovey-Dovey doesn't
sleep in a cage.
러비더비는 자기만의
둥지가 있어
No. Lovey-Dovey sleeps
in his very own nest,
창가에 있는
둥지를 옮겨야지
which I'm going to get
off the windowsill
내 방에 둘 거야
and put in my room.
안 그래, LD?
Isn't that right, LD?
안돼
No.
어디 가니?
Where are you going?
돌아와, 러비더비
Come back, Lovey-Dovey!
네 집은 여기야
This is your home now!
아마존에서 이미
새모이를 10kg 주문했다고
I already ordered 20 pounds
of bird feed off of Amazon!
떠났어
He's gone.
안됐다, 쉘든
I'm sorry, Sheldon.
나한테 어떻게 이럴 수 있지?
How could he do this to me?
내가 사랑할 수 있게
다시 돌아와, 이 새새끼야
Get back here, you stupid bird,
so I can love you!
(sighs)
영화를 보고
사람들도 만나고
Okay. So...
we went out,
saw a movie,
met some nice people,
서로에게 안 좋은
소리를 좀 했어
said horrible things
about each other in public...
꽤 아름다운 밤이였네
all in all,
a pretty magical night.
그래, 나도 잘못이 있지만
Okay, I'm not innocent
in all this,
넌 날 바보라 불렀어,
이 천식쟁이야
but you basically called me
stupid, you asthmatic dumbass.
좀 심했던 것 같네
I know, I-I-I crossed a line.
사과할게
And I'm sorry.
잠깐, 진심이야
No, no, no, hang on.
I really mean it.
우리가 사귀던 때랑 달라
And it's not like when we were
going out, I'd just apologize
섹스나 하려고
뭐든 사과하는 게 아냐
for everything
so we could end up in bed.
섹스는 고려할 것도 없이
100% 진심인 사과야
This is a 100%
sex-is-off-the-table
"I'm sorry."
알았어, 고마워
(sighs) All right. Thank you.
나도 미안해
I'm sorry, too.
섹스는 고려 대상 아니지?
Just to be clear,
sex is off the table, right?
꿈도 꾸지 마
Way off.
어쩌면 아직
친구로 지낼 수 없나봐
Maybe we're not ready
to hang out as friends.
초반에는 괜찮았는데
I don't know.
Up until the last part,
리드하는 레너드 말이야
I was kind of enjoying
take-charge Leonard
자신감 있어 보였어
with a little backbone.
영화도 고르고
의견도 내세우고
Picking the movie,
knowing what he wants,
조금 잘난 척도 하던데
a little cocky.
- 그래?
- 응
- Really?
- Yeah.
그럼 난 섹스도
옵션에 넣을래
Well, then, I'm putting
sex back on the table.
그건 어떻게 생각해?
What do you think about that?
좀 괜찮은데
Ooh. Maybe I like it.
네가 원하면
그런 남자가 될게
You do? Because if that's what
you like, I can be that guy.
네가 원한다면
뭐든 할 수 있어
I swear, I'll be anything
you want me to be.
잘자, 레너드
Good night, Leonard.
(door slams)
난 정말 멍청한 놈이야
I am such an asthmatic dumbass.
이상한 밤이였다
I had a weird night.
난 좋았어
Mine was great.
난 엄마가 될 거야
I'm going to be a mommy.
공대언니 블로그
http://tbbt.tistory.com
== sync, corrected by elderman ==